<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nikhil acharya</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nikhil acharya</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solana Token Transfer Indexer: Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/token-history-indexer-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/token-history-indexer-design/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In order to design an token transaction indexer, I will compare two existing indexers currently in operation at Helius: DAS (Digital Asset RPC Infrastructure) and Photon and cherry pick some of its features.&#xA;DAS is used to index all digital assets on Solana, including Tokens, NFTs, and cNFTs. You can explore more about DAS here. Photon is a new indexer launched by Helius to store compressed accounts. More details can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unikernels and Solana: A Hypothetical Exploration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-unikernels-in-solana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-unikernels-in-solana/</guid>
      <description>Unikernels and Solana: A Hypothetical Exploration Introduction I’ve always enjoyed pondering the &amp;ldquo;what-ifs&amp;rdquo; of technology and one area that has fascinated me for years is the concept of unikernels. Back in 2017-2018, I spent a lot of my free time researching unikernels. The idea of tailoring an application with only the necessary components of the kernel to create a lightweight, highly optimized library operating system (libOS) struck me as incredibly innovative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solana Token Transfer Indexer: Problem Statement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/token-history-problem-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/token-history-problem-statement/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement: Token Transfer History Indexer Background Retrieving transaction history for a specific wallet or multiple wallets on the Solana blockchain, especially for token transfers, currently requires multiple RPC calls and complicated filtering. This process is slow and inefficient, making it challenging to quickly access and filter token transfer data. There is a clear need for a streamlined and optimized method to retrieve token transfer history.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of how we fetch token transfer history specifically between two wallets today</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To copy or to clone? That&#39;s the question</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/copy-vs-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/copy-vs-clone/</guid>
      <description>I like having the rust-analyser fix issues for me. I hover over the code and see an issue like this&#xA;cannot move out of `host.metal_type` which is behind a shared reference move occurs because `host.metal_type` has type `std::option::Option&amp;lt;MetalType&amp;gt;`, which does not implement the `Copy trait` and the first thing I do is host.metal_type.clone() and that fixes the problem. But why does it fix the problem? What was the problem? Should I add a copy trait to my struct?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifetime vs Arc in Rust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/arc-vs-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 17:55:28 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/arc-vs-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Arc vs Lifetimes in Rust In Rust, both Arc and lifetimes are tools used to manage how data is shared or accessed across different parts of a program, but they serve different purposes and are used in different contexts.&#xA;1. Lifetimes Lifetimes in Rust are a way to ensure that references are always valid. They help the Rust compiler understand how long references to data should be valid to prevent dangling references, which could lead to undefined behavior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staking SOL on Solana in India: A Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/staking-sol-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 17:55:28 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/staking-sol-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Staking SOL on Solana: A Guide Staking on Solana is a process where you lock up your SOL tokens to support the network&amp;rsquo;s operations and, in return, earn rewards. While Helius is now the number one validator in Solana, it’s still challenging to stake SOL regularly. To know more about how to stake on Helius, see this blog.&#xA;Challenges in Staking SOL in India Despite the detailed staking instructions, acquiring Solana in a wallet remains a hurdle in India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blüdhaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/bludhaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/bludhaven/</guid>
      <description>History Blüdhaven was a former whaling town, which was officially incorporated as a &amp;ldquo;Commonwealth&amp;rdquo; in 1912. The town had a generally poor socio-economic populace, owing in part to failed efforts to transform itself into a manufacturing and shipping center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/hydra/</guid>
      <description>Motto Cut off one head and two will take their place</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tatooine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/tatooine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/tatooine/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away&amp;hellip;. A project was planned, but never completed</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
